Residing in Boulder, CO nathan@nathanfeaver.com (303)709-8421

Nathan Feaver

Ruby on Rails Web Developer

http://www.nathanfeaver.com http://www.vidusic.net http://github.com/ifeaver

Summary of Qualifications

Professional web developer for corporations working from front- to back-end (inquire about examples of work)

Web: HTML5, CSS3, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, AJAX, WordPress, and PHP

Coding: Ruby on Rails focused, Test Driven Development friendly, UNIX and command line friendly

Business: Product specification with clients, user experience design, B2C marketing

Experience

Ruby on Rails Developer

www.vidusic.net May 2012 to Present

- Architected, built, and deployed application for a music video blog in Ruby on Rails
- Used test driven development with RSpec and Factory Girl

Freelance Web Developer - WordPress

www.nathanfeaver.com

August 2011 to Present

- Created fully customized mobile-ready WordPress deployments for corporate and personal clients
- Developed Backend WYSIWIG tools for clients to easily maintain and update their site
- Designed custom WordPress themes to match the client's marketing and branding strategy
- Trained others to operate WordPress and maintain their new websites
- Tools built for fundraising campaigns, sharing news and upcoming events through social media, generating email lists, subscriber content, online scheduling
- Built a reading tool in JavaScript similar to Kindle Cloud Reader and Readability

Research Associate - Semiconductor Device and Nanofabrication Engineer

University of Colorado, Boulder

August 2008 to July 2011

- Developed MATLAB code to analyze block copolymer networks for connectivity, tortuosity, electrical resistance
- Developed novel fabrication process to create graphene nanoribbon transistors
- Precisely tuned silicon interfaces for block copolymer self-assembly and patterning below 30 nm
- Managed four undergraduate researchers, developing more efficient processing
- Taught lectures to 45 students and created in-class demonstrations for graduate level class

Education

Web Development Learning Opportunities:

- Various Meetup.com groups (Boulder Web Design, Code Retreat, Ruby on Beer, Boulder Ruby Group)
- RubyLearning.org (Ruby Core, Web Programming with Ruby)
- Saas-class.org (Topics: Web Development Architectures, Ruby on Rails, BDD and TDD)

University of Colorado, Boulder

August 2011

MS, Chemical and Biological Engineering, 3.7 GPA

Colorado School of Mines, Golden

May 2008

- BS, Chemical Engineering, cum laude, 3.5 GPA
- Special Academic Track in Polymers and Materials

Leadership

Co-Organizer – February 2011 to Present – Boulder Web Design (Meetup.com)

- Helped Organize Meetups for 50+ web designers
- Presented 'Mobile WordPress in a Snap' May 2012

Student Leader – August 2009 to May 2011 – Intervarsity Graduate Christian Fellowship

Contributed on core leadership team at a time when club doubled in size

NanoDays Volunteer – April 2010 – Colorado Nanofabrication Laboratory

Taught attending children and non-scientists about super hydrophobicity using nanoparticles

Head of Fundraising and Public Relations, Engineering Design Project – May 2006 to October 2006

- Created brand recognition and credibility through creative design of fund-raising pamphlet
- Raised over \$1.5k to fund the design and construction of trebuchet from local businesses and private donations
- Developed sponsorship levels and fundraising campaign to generate 4 corporate sponsors